<bill session="115" type="s" number="327" updated="2017-07-18T04:31:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to provide a safe harbor related to certain investment fund research reports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Reported by Senator Crapo with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="11">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="10"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="910"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-13T13:36:01Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to establish and implement a "safe harbor" for certain investment fund research reports published by brokers and dealers. Such reports shall be deemed not to be "offers" under specified provisions of securities law, even if the broker or dealer participates in the registered offering of the investment fund's securities.

In implementing the safe harbor, the SEC must prohibit a self-regulatory organization from maintaining or enforcing a rule that would prevent a member from: (1) publishing or distributing a covered investment fund research report solely because the member is also participating in a registered offering of the fund,&#160;or (2) participating in a registered offering of a covered investment fund solely because the member has published a research report about the fund.

The bill restricts the SEC from conditioning the safe harbor upon specified requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
