<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="16" updated="2017-07-22T15:56:10Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-01-11T17:50:56-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000289"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-01-11"/>
  <description>Page 39, line 3, insert after "made by agencies." the following: "If the reviewing court determines that a statutory or regulatory provision relevant to its decision contains a gap or ambiguity, the court shall not interpret that gap or ambiguity as an implicit delegation to the agency of legislative rule making authority and shall not rely on such gap or ambiguity as a justification either for interpreting agency authority expansively or for deferring to the agency's interpretation on the question of law.".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 115-2 to revise section 2 of title II of the bill to restrain unwarranted interpretation of ambiguous statutes to find implied delegations of legislative rulemaking authority, and of ambiguous statutes and regulations to expansively extend agency authority.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-01-11T17:50:56-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="35">
      <text>On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 185 (Roll no. 35).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T15:08:53-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H344-347, H364" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H344" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11"/>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T17:50:56-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Goodlatte amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 185 (Roll no. 35).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T17:50:56-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T17:50:56-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T15:08:53-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Goodlatte.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
