<bill session="115" type="h" number="601" updated="2017-06-19T22:30:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24T17:10:24-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-24T17:10:24-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the transparency and accelerate the impact of assistance provided under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to promote quality basic education in developing countries, to better enable such countries to achieve universal access to quality basic education and improved learning outcomes, to eliminate duplication and waste, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">READ Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24T16:52:18-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce (CA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24T16:52:40-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H662-666" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24T16:52:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 601.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-24T17:10:24-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H662-664" label="text of measure as passed"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24T17:10:26-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="116">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 116.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="623"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T13:54:44Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act or the READ Act

 (Sec. 3) This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to state that it shall be U.S. policy to work with partner countries, other donors, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations (including faith-based organizations) to promote basic education through programs that: (1) respond to the needs and capacities of developing countries to improve literacy and other basic skills; (2) strengthen educational systems, expand access to safe learning environments (including by breaking down barriers to basic education for women and girls), and support the engagement of parents in their children's education; (3) promote education as a foundation for economic growth; and (4) monitor and evaluate the effectiveness and quality of basic education programs in partner countries.

 (Sec. 4) The President shall: (1) seek to improve the effectiveness of assistance by coordinating relevant executive branch efforts, (2) ensure that assistance is aligned with U.S. foreign policy and economic interests, and (3) submit to Congress by October 1, 2017, a comprehensive FY2018 through FY2022 strategy to promote basic education in partner countries.

 (Sec. 5) The bill establishes within the U.S. Agency for International Development the position of Senior Coordinator of United States International Basic Education Assistance, who shall have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of U.S. government resources and activities relating to the promotion of international basic education.

 (Sec. 6) The President shall ensure that programs carried out under the comprehensive strategy: (1) apply monitoring and evaluation methodologies to determine if programs and activities accomplish measurable improvements in literacy, numeracy, or other basic skills development; and (2) include funding for both short- and long-term monitoring and evaluation.

 (Sec. 7) The President shall submit to Congress an annual implementation report.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
