<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="40" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="78" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-01-12T15:40:53-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the SEC consider the protection of investors, in addition to promoting efficiency, competition, and capital formation when conducting such a review and also expressly instructs the SEC to consider the public interest, the protection of investors as well as the promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation when conducting such a review of existing SEC regulations.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 115-3 to require the SEC consider the protection of investors, in addition to promoting efficiency, competition, and capital formation when conducting such a review and also expressly instructs the SEC to consider the public interest, the protection of investors as well as the promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation when conducting such a review of existing SEC regulations.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-01-12T15:40:53-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Velazquez amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T15:36:20-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Ms. Velazquez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H439" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H439" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12"/>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T15:36:20-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Ms. Velazquez.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T15:40:53-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Velazquez amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T15:40:53-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
