<bill session="115" type="sr" number="114" updated="2017-07-19T05:42:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on humanitarian crises in Nigeria, Somalia, South Sudan, and Yemen.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on humanitarian crises in Nigeria, Somalia, South Sudan, and Yemen.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2368-2369" label="text as introduced in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="115">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 115.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Nigeria"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 the United States should lead an international diplomatic effort to address obstacles in Nigeria, Somalia, South Sudan, and Yemen that are preventing delivery of humanitarian aid; the President should encourage other governments to join the United States in providing the resources necessary to meet the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs appeal to address the humanitarian crises in those countries; and the President should work with international partners to document violations of international humanitarian law in those countries and bring perpetrators to justice. Urges the President to:

 persuade the government of South Sudan to stop blocking aid; notify Congress if that government does not immediately respect international humanitarian law; press the government of Nigeria to ensure accountability for security forces that violate human rights and fail to cooperate with international aid efforts; send a high level representative to the United Kingdom's Ministerial Conference on Somalia and publicly announce a contribution to the humanitarian assistance efforts; and work with stakeholders to persuade parties to conflict in Yemen to permit humanitarian groups increased access to Red Sea ports to deliver much-needed assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
