<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="34" updated="2017-07-18T18:56:09Z">
  <amends type="h" number="238" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-01-12T17:18:49-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001062"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <description>Amendment makes clear that the Commission may impose and implement position limits as it finds necessary, provided the Commission makes a finding prior to imposing such limits. It makes no changes to the longstanding federal position limits regime for the enumerated agricultural commodities or the existing statutory requirements that Designated Contract Markets impose position limits or accountability levels on all contracts.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in Part B of House Report 115-3 to make clear Congress's intent that the Commission may impose and implement position limits as it finds necessary, provided the Commission makes a finding prior to imposing such limits. It makes no changes to the longstanding federal position limits regime for the enumerated agricultural commodities or the existing statutory requirements that Designated Contract Markets impose position limits or accountability levels on all contracts.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-01-12T17:18:49-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="52">
      <text>On agreeing to the Conaway amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 236 - 191 (Roll no. 52).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:39:09-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Conaway.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H423-424" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H423" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12"/>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:39:09-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Conaway.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:18:49-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Conaway amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 236 - 191 (Roll no. 52).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:18:49-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:18:49-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
