<bill session="115" type="h" number="2582" updated="2017-07-27T07:13:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the State of Utah to select certain lands that are available for disposal under the Pony Express Resource Management Plan to be used for the support and benefit of State institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act 

This bill allows the state of Utah to select certain lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior that are identified as available for disposal by land exchange in the Record of Decision for the Pony Express Resource Management Plan and Rangeland Program Summary for Utah County, as amended by the Pony Express Plan Amendment (November 1997), in fulfillment of certain land grants made to Utah upon being admitted as a state, including for the establishment of certain state institutions, including certain local schools, under the Act of July 16, 1894, without further land use planning action by the BLM.

The criteria listed in Decision 3 of the Lands Program of the resource management plan shall not apply to any lands selected by Utah pursuant to this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
