<amendment session="115" chamber="h" number="4" updated="2017-07-22T15:56:11Z">
  <amends type="h" number="26" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2017-01-05T19:17:56-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <offered datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to require an accounting of the greenhouse gas emission impacts associated with a rule as well as an analysis of the impacts on low-income and rural communities. Also, if the rule increases carbon dioxide by a certain amount or increases the risk of certain health impacts to low-income or rural communities, then the rule is defined as a major rule.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 115-1 to require an accounting of the greenhouse gas emission impacts associated with a rule as well as an analysis of the impacts on low-income and rural communities. If the rule increases carbon dioxide by a certain amount or increases the risk of certain health impacts to low-income or rural communities, then the rule is defined as a major rule.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2017-01-05T19:17:56-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="13">
      <text>On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 230 (Roll no. 13).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05T15:56:19-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Grijalva.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H136-137, H166" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H136" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05"/>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05T19:17:56-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05T19:17:56-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05T19:17:56-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 230 (Roll no. 13).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05T15:56:19-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Grijalva.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
