<bill session="115" type="s" number="1359" updated="2017-07-28T20:27:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the John F. Kennedy Center Act to authorize appropriations for the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2017-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">John F. Kennedy Center Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill amends the John F. Kennedy Center Act to reauthorize appropriations for FY2018-FY2021 for maintenance, repair, and security, and capital projects for the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts.

The bill directs that a plaque be placed within the Kennedy Center that contains an inscription to commemorate the 60th anniversary of the signing of the National Cultural Center Act by President Dwight D. Eisenhower. The Kennedy Center must solicit private contributions for the design, procurement, and installation of the plaque.

The Kennedy Center may create displays and programs that memorialize its opening in 1971 and its programmatic legacy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
